[SPEAKER_04]: So, if you ever think about what I was saying yesterday, the... what's the... what's the point of the practice?
[SPEAKER_04]: What's the measurable point?
[SPEAKER_04]: What does the successful practice result in?
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, obviously, there are many ways you can answer this, but let's just start answering it.
[SPEAKER_04]: One way would be not being bothered as much.
[SPEAKER_04]: And how that... how is that practically measured, in terms of insight, that the suttas will talk about?
[SPEAKER_04]: How would you know that you're along the right lines?
[SPEAKER_04]: I mean, yeah, because what can happen is, you know, people can own a kind of practice, because they got inspired to practice, but they will kind of inadvertently still be addressing the circumstances, avoiding and so on, and in the end, like, build up a little environment that nothing bothers them.
[SPEAKER_04]: And then everything is sort of at the arm's length, so then they feel like, oh, look, my practice is succeeding, because I don't suffer as much, factually.
[SPEAKER_02]: But over time, you do it, you know, one, two, three years, you start being able to manage things.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, exactly.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what I mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, you become a bit more hardened, a hardened individual.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: But so you wouldn't, you wouldn't say that, you wouldn't, you wouldn't, you couldn't use that as a, as I said, as a measure of successful practice.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, because what insight do you have?
[SPEAKER_00]: What about if your mind moves on account of the thought of you dying?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, how then... what insight is required for the mind to not move on account of the thought of dying?
[SPEAKER_04]: What is the culminating insight there?
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what is often talked about.
[SPEAKER_03]: Anicca.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, what's the insight of that anicca?
[SPEAKER_04]: What the anicca and dukkha culminate in?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, it's the not-self.
[SPEAKER_04]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, that is the measure.
[SPEAKER_04]: The complete cessation, well, first of the self-view, then your notions of personality and conceit.
[SPEAKER_04]: And when that is absent, completely gone, without any traces, then, yeah, you couldn't suffer even if you want to.
[SPEAKER_03]: So, it is the measure that the less somebody takes things personally, the more they are progressing in the practice?
[SPEAKER_04]: Could be.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, you know, you have, like, psychotherapeutical methods that teach you how to not take things personally.
[SPEAKER_04]: But you're taking that personally.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, there has to be an actual insight into anatta.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's, like, not...
[SPEAKER_04]: It's not something you can stumble upon accidentally, that anatta.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's where you need the learning, you need the yonisu, manasikāra, you need practice, sense of strength.
[SPEAKER_04]: But yeah, it's a factual, irreversible insight, to put it that way.
[SPEAKER_04]: And yeah, the whole anicca, sīla, anicca, dukkha, it's just so that you can actually experience the anatta.
[SPEAKER_04]: So then, what is anatta?
[SPEAKER_00]: Can I... because it... that is really what makes the difference.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not... it's not like... yeah, because I've talked about this before, how you can say, okay, my mind... your mind won't be bothered by, let's say, even the thought of dying, but it's more fundamental than just, sort of,
[SPEAKER_00]: But now, nothing bothers you.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's necessary.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's a prerequisite for the inside of...
[SPEAKER_04]: But, as the Buddha said himself, in other, you know, dispensations at the time, there were teachers that you could factually establish neither perception nor perception.
[SPEAKER_04]: That means you're pretty much unbothered by anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: Anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: Anything inferior to that, as the suttas would say.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he said, only in his teaching, only in this presentation of the Buddhas, you will get the anatta part inside.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, yes, yeah, when I'm being bothered, and even the suttas say, you know, Arahant's mind does not get overwhelmed by things, Arahant's mind overwhelms things and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's a factual strength that is developed, that obviously without which you couldn't understand and
[SPEAKER_04]: You fully developed the anatta, but there is that part of anatta.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, say, you have been sense restraints in the day and exercise for guarding the senses, keeping the precepts, learning in solitude.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, okay, you're meeting the requirements, let's say like that, to start seeing atta slash anatta, attavada, abandoning it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, what is that?
[SPEAKER_04]: This is like something that would just occur and then you could interpret it in hindsight or do you need to know where to look for in order to see it and then start looking up until you recognize it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, let's start.
[SPEAKER_04]: What's the necessary basis for an atta?
[SPEAKER_01]: Seeing atta?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Peripheral?
[SPEAKER_01]: So, what is atta then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's define that first.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's always peripheral.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't put it in front of you.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, the properties of atta, the properties of the sense of self, would be...
[SPEAKER_04]: It's not directly visible.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, you can't actually see with your senses.
[SPEAKER_04]: You can't observe it with your five senses and you certainly can't just... oh, yeah, this is myself that I'm just relating to.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's always ambiguous.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: What else?
[SPEAKER_04]: Atta, the sense of self.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's the center of experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, but let's not speak theoretically.
[SPEAKER_04]: Let's instead... like, everybody now has a sense of self to some degree, I presume.
[SPEAKER_04]: Describe.
[SPEAKER_04]: What is it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I would say that it's automatic.
[SPEAKER_01]: Unless one is actively seeking to clarify that ambiguous sense of self, it is, yeah, it is automatically.
[SPEAKER_01]: Automatic.
[SPEAKER_01]: In the sense that whenever you experience
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure, sure.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, we're talking about the sense of self that lingers always in the background of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, regardless of your reactions.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you have the experience of when that self's not there?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's always, to some degree, you know, sometimes might feel clearer, sometimes might not, but that sense of I am, sense of self, sense of the, yeah, center of the experience, it's always there.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, but do you see it right now, as we speak?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you see your own sense of self, enduring there, on its own, somehow, somewhere, ambiguously, just kind of lingering?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you have it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you have that sense of self?
[SPEAKER_03]: To some degree.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, and that's the key there, basically.
[SPEAKER_04]: The way to start seeing it is to learn how to see it on its own degree, not how to make it into an object that I think it should be of my observation, of my direct attention.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's the, again, the solitude and the practice of mindfulness, as we said before.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, as we said yesterday, in particular, you know,
[SPEAKER_04]: Mindfulness is memory of your present experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's what sati is.
[SPEAKER_04]: There's nothing complicated about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: If you were to abandon the views of mindfulness being the concentrating on the present moment, I'm mindful and I'm here, I'm here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Having the memory of the present moment right here while we speak, that's where the mind... that's where mindfulness is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Practice of memory here and now.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's like a a different way, a different angle, let's say like that, of attending to
[SPEAKER_04]: What is here and now in front of me directly attended.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's not something you can... like if I ask you recall a memory or something, just remember something, where would you... how would you do that?
[SPEAKER_04]: Would you stare at things and feel the sensations of the body and focus to get memory?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: You would quite opposite, unfocus from what you were focused on.
[SPEAKER_04]: To recall, recollect what is there, that point of view of memory,
[SPEAKER_04]: Whether it's memory of this second while I'm saying memory, memory, memory, it's there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Or it's the memory from ten years ago.
[SPEAKER_04]: Doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's the same point of view.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's the point of view that you can use to observe the present experience at the same time you are in the present experience, just indirectly.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's the background of your current absorbed attention point of view, of your senses.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's the contact.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's where the mind is.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that ambiguous sense of self is kind of here and there, neither here nor there, in between the two.
[SPEAKER_04]: If you're of the view that that sense of self is something you can think directly, something you can access your senses directly, something you can attend, observe and see it as anatta, you're not seeing the sense of self.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're just chasing the idea that you have intellectually developed.
[SPEAKER_04]: of it, on account of, you know, reading the suttas and so on, listening to the talks.
[SPEAKER_04]: The point is, Tantra Self is always behind from where you're looking.
[SPEAKER_04]: But then, when you realize that the range, for lack of a better word,
[SPEAKER_04]: of where you can look is either directly attended or the direction of that memory point of view, sati, you realize, oh, you don't need to know specifically where the sense of self is.
[SPEAKER_04]: You know that it will have to be between the two points of view.
[SPEAKER_04]: They're there at the same time.
[SPEAKER_04]: As we said yesterday, with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's not that the memory point of view, where the mind is, comes first, in a sense, it exists on its own, and then the senses come up.
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: They exist simultaneously.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, yeah, one is the way of the direct attention, that you can access the world.
[SPEAKER_04]: The other one is the knowledge of you with the direct attention, that you can access the world.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's why sati memory is used interchangeably in the suttas.
[SPEAKER_04]: The problem is that people, when they hear the memory, they have a view of past, implicit past.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, even if it's the past, it's presently recollected.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, you realize, okay, so, I could technically, as a practice, instead of only recollecting the past, I could recollect what is presently enduring.
[SPEAKER_04]: Just not allow myself to directly attend it, but know it on the level of memory.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, are you seated now?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's memory, see?
[SPEAKER_04]: The immediate answer, you don't need to, wait, I need to feel my knees.
[SPEAKER_04]: The recognition of that simultaneously enduring point of view is there.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's like two points of observance of the same thing.
[SPEAKER_04]: And because there are two, neither can be one in charge, master, experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Without this, this wouldn't be.
[SPEAKER_04]: Either way, there's no room for ownership.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, that's all good and well in theory and that aspect, but...
[SPEAKER_04]: So, yes, practically, let's say you start practicing sati correctly,
[SPEAKER_04]: In the solitude, you're recollecting what you're presently doing, instead of attending to what you're presently doing.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, keeping that peripheral point of view, watching what is presently, you know, sitting, breathing, whatever.
[SPEAKER_04]: Memory of breathing, ānāpānasati.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's exactly what it is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Memory of current breathing.
[SPEAKER_04]: But not accessing it to the point of view of directly attending the sensations of it, but accessing it to the indirect point of view of knowledge of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: The recognition of the of the images of breathing that you're doing, basically.
[SPEAKER_04]: The memory.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's what memory is.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, the sense of self, the atta, however ambiguous it might be, however fleeting or unclear it might be, it is real as such, as I keep saying.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, instead of you trying to see it on the level of directly attended experience, or myself, myself, you need to see it for whatever it is, however it is, a vague cloud,
[SPEAKER_04]: Sometimes more palpable, sometimes not.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the sense of self, sense of I am, is there lingering.
[SPEAKER_04]: And you can't go behind it, in other words.
[SPEAKER_04]: You can't become the observer of it and put it as an object.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's always going to be behind you.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, how do you make it then not perpetually escape from you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I think this elusivity
[SPEAKER_01]: It's important in terms of seeing it in its own terms.
[SPEAKER_01]: So... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, first you realize, okay, so I cannot not...
[SPEAKER_04]: I cannot make it not elusive.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's gonna stay elusive.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, I need to accept ambiguity of it as its characteristic.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, ambiguity should be enough for me to recognize it as being there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because everybody recognizes it ambiguously, but then it has the pressure, the impulse, the tendency to...
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, let me clarify it.
[SPEAKER_04]: The only way I can relate to it is if it is more defined.
[SPEAKER_04]: But it's not.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's an ambiguous phenomenon.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's neither here nor there, but it is real as such.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, that's why you shouldn't dismiss it, nor should you try to, like, overly define it and you should certainly not mystify it.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's still a phenomenon, like any other thing, any other image in the mind.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, if you keep trying to directly access it, it's always going to slip through your fingers.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, how do you then access it without
[SPEAKER_04]: You know, grabbing it, so to speak.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like you say about memories, so there's already... By surmounting it, in a sense that we just described, and recognizing exactly memory.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, so, the knowledge of it, the recognition there is an ambiguous thing that's neither in my senses nor away from it.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's kind of always there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, but wherever it is,
[SPEAKER_04]: It has to be in between, has to be within this and this.
[SPEAKER_04]: It has to be between what I'm directly attending and the knowledge, the memory of what I'm directly attending.
[SPEAKER_04]: Cannot be outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Recollect that factually, on the basis of your currently enduring ambiguous sense of self, not just theoretically, frequently enough and well in solitude,
[SPEAKER_04]: When you're recollecting it frequently enough, and once you establish that fact... idea, that it's fact... based on the... the factual ambiguity of the sense of self.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, this sense of self that, you know, I'm not trying to define, but I'm not ignoring either, has to be between this and this.
[SPEAKER_04]: And let that endure, and when you forget it, re-establish it again, and again, and again.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's how you basically
[SPEAKER_04]: aprut.
[SPEAKER_04]: Aprut, not the sense of self immediately, but aprut the view that the sense of self can be outside.
[SPEAKER_04]: Outside of this, outside of experience at all, outside of the five aggregates, whichever way you want to define it, you just know it cannot be outside.
[SPEAKER_04]: If I look that way, or if I look the memory way, those are the two ends.
[SPEAKER_04]: Nothing can be outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, although the sense of self feels
[SPEAKER_04]: Inaccessible directly, and it's always there, and none of this pertains to it.
[SPEAKER_04]: It has to be within this.
[SPEAKER_04]: Cannot be outside of it, because all I have is this and this.
[SPEAKER_04]: How can I even know outside?
[SPEAKER_04]: Because even the thought of outside, of this experience and external world and so on, it's within this and this.
[SPEAKER_04]: Within me directly attending it and having the memory of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: There is no outside of that.
[SPEAKER_04]: You know, that's all that appears.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like what's in front?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, and a lot more appears in between, but not outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: And when I say in between, I don't mean in a third place in between the two.
[SPEAKER_04]: It means on the basis of these two simultaneous things.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's what the Buddha described.
[SPEAKER_04]: Nāmarūpa, viññāṇa, viññāṇa, nāmarūpa.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like they did mutually.
[SPEAKER_04]: There is no first one which comes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like two sticks leaning on each other equally.
[SPEAKER_04]: So they can't remain standing if you remove one.
[SPEAKER_01]: To expand a bit on what you mean by these two directions, maybe it's useful to use the
[SPEAKER_01]: Like these two common wrong views, for example, of empiricism or idealism, the idea that there is an external world outside of your reality.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, that's the point.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, you would say the materialism or that kind of external point of view, scientific view, it's always on the basis of the attention, direct attention and the senses.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then, you could have solipsism, or idealism, or all sorts of variations.
[SPEAKER_04]: There will be... No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's my mental comes first.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, no.
[SPEAKER_04]: They're simultaneous to the same extent.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the point.
[SPEAKER_04]: To the same extent.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's patitsaṁupādā in the nutshell.
[SPEAKER_04]: With this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Without this, this wouldn't be.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the recognition.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, the arahant does not destroy these two things to become an arahant.
[SPEAKER_04]: He just fully removes any trace of ignorance in regard to it.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: And practically, again, as opposed to theoretically, this, this, and that, and external world, internal world, and both at the same time, it's, yeah, what you're currently attending to, is like this seated body here and now, and I can think about this seated body here and now.
[SPEAKER_04]: I can have a memory of it here and now.
[SPEAKER_04]: I can have a memory what that here and now was yesterday, what this here and now was two days ago, maybe even more.
[SPEAKER_04]: And the more I withdraw from and expand my mind from the senses, I can have a memory that would go even past this life.
[SPEAKER_03]: The point is, it's still within the same two points of view that are there simultaneously present.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, if you... That's all you have, by the way.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's all you ever had.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's just that there is a confusion and all this sort of net of messy view and what comes first and what second and everything else in between.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, generally, that results into the
[SPEAKER_04]: The weight of the experience being put on that sense of self as the owner, as that's outside of this point of view.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, sense of self can remember, sense of self can attend, can do both, can look in between.
[SPEAKER_04]: But if you realize that even that sense of self, as ambiguous as it is, it is still an arisen phenomena that you can have a memory of.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's actually an object, not of direct attention, but
[SPEAKER_04]: In its own regard, it is real as such as a thing that exists in your mind.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, and if so, means you are not it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Fundamentally and technically.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, you can say, okay, there's no sense of self.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's like, well, no, there is sense of self.
[SPEAKER_04]: You just need to stop putting it first, find that upon which it depends, and see that... See, two points of view.
[SPEAKER_04]: Just seeing your experience is fundamentally determined simultaneously by two points of view at once.
[SPEAKER_04]: One of the memory, one of the direct attention, means neither of them can take place as the center of master experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: Impossible.
[SPEAKER_04]: When there are two, they cannot be one only.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because they are equal twos.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, then, any notion of the external world, any notion of scientific observation, any views that you have, has to be within it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Any notion of solipsist world, on fire and first hunger, has to be within the two.
[SPEAKER_04]: But teach somebody.
[SPEAKER_04]: And often, like when people
[SPEAKER_04]: Ask the Buddha about the... the sense of self, because they heard that's what he teaches, so āvat-sanārtha.
[SPEAKER_04]: If they were, like, really wrong, if they said, oh, if Master Gautama says there is no self, are you implying that no self is this self, or any other mystification, he would just be silent.
[SPEAKER_04]: But on some other occasions, people did ask him kind of the same question, and he replied, but not to their question.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I remember first time, a long time ago, I was still learning, I was reading the Sutas, I was puzzled, why... why does he give this seemingly non
[SPEAKER_04]: As a reply to the question of what is self, what is anatta.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, he would say, with this, this is, with the rising of ignorance, saṅkhara, with saṅkhara, viññāṇa, viññāṇa, nāmarūpa.
[SPEAKER_04]: I was like, so, but why would you, why would you give that as an answer to where is my sense of self?
[SPEAKER_04]: And then he goes, well, this is why.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's what it is.
[SPEAKER_04]: If you undermine with this, this is, if you fully understand it, there is no outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: If you fully abandon it, yeah, that's how you get the not-self that you're asking about.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's the most direct answer to what not-self is, to how to be developed.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, of course, you know, the Buddha being the Buddha could describe this with this, this is, but it's still upādāna.
[SPEAKER_04]: In many sort of more kind of subtle details and pairs and whatever else is sort of traditionally assumed.
[SPEAKER_04]: But it's just describing the aspects and everything else that depends upon those... with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: And everything else that depends is the entire saṃsāra.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's the birth, aging, death.
[SPEAKER_04]: In another, in another sutta, he doesn't actually describe it, Sampada, in these twelve factors, but from birth goes into taking up sticks and stones and killing each other and harming and everything that happens in the world.
[SPEAKER_04]: In another sutta, doesn't even go to avijja, just stops with nāmarūpa, viññāṇa, viññāṇa, nāmarūpa, contemplating that purification of the mind, cessation of the notions of self.
[SPEAKER_04]: Fundamentally, all you need to contemplate is with this, this is on the right level.
[SPEAKER_04]: With what?
[SPEAKER_04]: With what, what is?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, with this that I'm directly attending to, my experience as a whole, there is the image of the experience as a whole.
[SPEAKER_04]: There is the memory of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Simultaneously present.
[SPEAKER_04]: Otherwise, you wouldn't even know experience as a whole that you're attending to, as the experience as a whole that you attended to.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's why it's simultaneous.
[SPEAKER_04]: One feeds the other.
[SPEAKER_04]: One defines the other.
[SPEAKER_04]: If there are no senses there that are attending and sort of operating
[SPEAKER_04]: In their own domain, there would be nothing to have an image of.
[SPEAKER_04]: If there is no image, recollection, memory of the senses and the world that the senses are in, well, nothing would be intelligible.
[SPEAKER_04]: You would not be a conscious being.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, now, anything that happens throughout the day, you make sure it stays within the context of with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: With this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: And there is a sutta when the Buddha says, and he wouldn't go in more details, he would just question monks.
[SPEAKER_04]: Monks, do you see with this, this has arisen?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you see that with this, as a present condition, this has to be?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you see that without this, this isn't?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Monks, that view, as pure as it is, as precise as it is, if you were to not maintain it, practice it, cultivate it further, but just sort of
[SPEAKER_04]: Venerate it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Would that result in liberation?
[SPEAKER_04]: No, it wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, monks, don't just venerate it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Keep doing it.
[SPEAKER_04]: And he described that as the cleanest, purest view.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because he doesn't have these secondary definitions.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Every Pārthitam Upāda starts with that phrase.
[SPEAKER_04]: With this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: To both present tenses.
[SPEAKER_04]: And then with what?
[SPEAKER_04]: And then he goes into the standard descriptions and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the principle remains unchanged.
[SPEAKER_04]: Despite what they're sort of, you know,
[SPEAKER_04]: The principle of two simultaneously present things, paticca upāna, paticca upāna, it remains.
[SPEAKER_04]: Whether you're talking about birth and death, or nāmarūpa, viññāṇa, the principle of this, this is, and everything else is in between.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's where the monk who practices that rightly, establishes that he doesn't take I to be first I, my own, or forms in the world,
[SPEAKER_04]: Whereas, if you ignore...
[SPEAKER_01]: You have defaulted back to your perversion of the order, of putting your own sense of self first, or whatever else.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whereas, if you're not ignoring it, you cannot do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: If you make the effort to not ignore the order, and whatever you're experiencing, on the basis of sensory strength, virtue, solitude, you include
[SPEAKER_04]: In the order of what this is, there is no outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: It doesn't matter if it's more on the mental memory side, more on the palpable side.
[SPEAKER_04]: It doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, as we keep saying, content doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_04]: The nature of things matters.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, it's present as such.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's all that matters.
[SPEAKER_04]: You know, whichever way it feels, it's got to be felt within this and this.
[SPEAKER_04]: No outside of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: And when I think, oh, there's no outside of it, as in outside of it, that's within the enduring body here and the memory of the enduring body here.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's still enclosed within the same principle.
[SPEAKER_04]: The moment you hammer in, whereby you cannot forget, let's say like that, that there is no outside of this and this, that's where your Rādhāvāda is gone.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, so you can't... you still continue to operate externally.
[SPEAKER_04]: You might well still look the same.
[SPEAKER_04]: But your assumption of external to this and this is now inconceivable, because it is inconceivable.
[SPEAKER_04]: Conceiving it is seen within this, because you have developed the perspective of this and this sufficiently enough to include the wildest of your careless fantasy, imagination, assumption.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's still seen, rightly, as second within this.
[SPEAKER_04]: And now, if you sustain, invest the effort, purify, establish, endure that view more, throughout, there will be no more even room for any slightest traces of conceit to remain.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because, you know, you might have abandoned the view of the external entity, of me, existing independent of this.
[SPEAKER_04]: You still have this, like, subtler habits, leanings, cravings, and so on, that kind of imply, to that much subtler degree, sort of independence.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's still within, but it's a bit... but you realize, no, even that cannot stand.
[SPEAKER_04]: If the principle of paticampāda is thoroughly developed, dhamma is fulfilled.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's exactly as the suttas say.
[SPEAKER_04]: One who sees paticampāda sees the dhamma.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: No delay there.
[SPEAKER_04]: And it's the direct most, as I said, as the Buddha said, the purest thing, the view that if you cultivate, it will... can only result in the complete purification of your being.
[SPEAKER_04]: Removal and cessation of passion, greed, aversion and delusion.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because all of those things imply a degree of that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Conceit, self-centeredness, some degree of
[SPEAKER_04]: Could it be correctly said, thus, the removal of ātavāda is
[SPEAKER_00]: To see that view of Pāṭiccasamuppāda, rightly as you described, and then it's almost... then you don't need the view anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't have even that pure view anymore, if even that conceits unfulfilled.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because you would be it.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the sense, like, practitioner or somebody, it's what you are.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm talking about the arahant.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, sure, sure.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's what you are.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, arahant, when there are no more traces of conceit left, well, even that view is not...
[SPEAKER_04]: It's now redundant.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He doesn't need to recollect and re-establish that view, because there's nothing perverting it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, he goes beyond the view.
[SPEAKER_00]: He is it.
[SPEAKER_04]: There is a sutta that says it, isn't there?
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, the Noble Eightfold Path, I think in Vajra
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, two more factors.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's what it's... And one of them is, like, gone beyond the view.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, liberation and loss and vision of liberation.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes, something like that.
[SPEAKER_04]: And when that was described, it was like, he has gone beyond the view, which means even the right view, the right, it's gone.
[SPEAKER_04]: He doesn't have it anymore, because he has no wrong reference in regard to it anymore, to define it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whereas even one who would see that, kind of still has the other reference, or still sees it to a degree.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, to that extent, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: So he still needs to lean and work and cultivate onto the side of the right.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he can never really fall back onto the other effort.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, he can fall back up to the, you know, to the factors that he has abandoned.
[SPEAKER_04]: He can't fall back beyond that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Sotāpanna can abandon his training and become careless and not, not, not invest more effort into sustaining and purifying of this view that he has.
[SPEAKER_04]: But what he cannot do is, whatever he engages in here, he cannot spill outside with the assumptions and the attavāda, the external self, the over there.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's inconceivable.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because even when one has those thoughts,
[SPEAKER_04]: They're seen on the background of the memory of this, this is.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's effortless.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's seen.
[SPEAKER_03]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_03]: It cannot not be seen.
[SPEAKER_04]: Effort is on the level of acting out of the habits, pressures and passions, including trying to get rid of them directly through all sorts of practices and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the effort.
[SPEAKER_04]: You make the effort to not do that.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the view in itself requires no effort.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, because it's not like a view that you hold as... in the sense of any kind of view about the world that you... Well, in a way, any view is effortless.
[SPEAKER_04]: The worldly views are effortless.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's why they're so hard to uproot, because you don't even... you don't even see how you're doing it, because in a way, you're not doing it directly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, so that's not what makes the difference to whether it's effortless or not, it's what... Well, it's right or wrong.
[SPEAKER_04]: Whether it's contradicting the actual, I don't know, order of things, arrangement of the aggregates, the
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's why dhamma is used interchangeably as phenomena and as the knowledge of the way out.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, exactly.
[SPEAKER_04]: The dhamma.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, because they're both still phenomena.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's phenomena, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's just rightly established, right order of phenomena and wrong order of phenomena.
[SPEAKER_04]: There is no third option.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, if the right order of phenomena is established, where this is, dispassion will have to be an inevitable result.
[SPEAKER_04]: You know, as the... what was that?
[SPEAKER_04]: The simile where it gives, like, as the mountains, kind of, the river slopes down the mountain, it goes into that direction, has to go that way, because that's where the mountain slopes.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, if, you know, if your slope is upon the... established upon the right order, the mind will have to slope towards nibbāna, towards dispassion, towards cooling down, towards removal of ownership and any traces of ownership of ātma, basically.
[SPEAKER_04]: When the ownership of that phenomenon we started describing, that ambiguous sense of self, the fact, the moment you start seeing it as an ambiguous phenomenon that endures there, peripherally, neither here nor there, but know that it's between the two, yeah, that's already the beginning of relinquishing it, relinquishing the ownership of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's why I keep saying, in the past talks, you don't remove the atta, like, oh, that phenomenon is gone.
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: You remove the ownership of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Thus, atta becomes un-atta.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the thing is there.
[SPEAKER_04]: The creature, the individual, whatever you want to call it, it's still there.
[SPEAKER_04]: That ambiguous sense of self of these five aggregates, of these memories and future plans and everything else remains there.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's just not thoroughly not... well, thoroughly impossible to own.
[SPEAKER_04]: Any other directions to go to?
[SPEAKER_04]: Other questions?
[SPEAKER_01]: So, I have often thought about these two directions in terms of...
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, it's important to clarify that it's direction, in the sense that you never access them.
[SPEAKER_04]: They're there, they're only... And even if you're, like, not necessarily thinking about either of them, you realize you are within them.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Your non-thinking, your ignoring, your distraction is within the...
[SPEAKER_04]: This and this is, within what's presently attended to, even in unawareness, and the memory of it, while it's presently unattended to, even in unawareness.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there's, so there's, there's always simultaneously six of these, what you're attending to, in the sixth sense, right?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, yeah, but we don't need to complicate it that way, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, what do you think about, um, so defining it in this,
[SPEAKER_01]: The direction of what you're attending to, and the direction of where attention is coming from, how, I mean, that, that, that... Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, exactly.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's what yoniso is, the womb of what you're looking at.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's simultaneously present as what this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Right.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, what you're looking at, this experience, what you're touching, feeling, sensing, sensing, and so on, it's there, where that image is.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's not in you.
[SPEAKER_04]: In me is there, where that image is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's just outside and more outside, so to speak, internally speaking.
[SPEAKER_04]: Inaccessible, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, inaccessible.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's why the, what was it, the description of an arahant, one who is completely developed and fulfilled and abandon everything to be abandoned on account of seeing this and this is, it says for him all that's left is this, this body, this conscious body, this thing.
[SPEAKER_04]: And all the name and form externally.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, it's just... the more you practice these two internal points of view, attention and memory, attention-memory, attention-memory, attention-memory, simultaneous present, the more external the whole thing is becoming.
[SPEAKER_04]: They'll become two external points of view and thus there's nothing in me that's already external to my own sense of self.
[SPEAKER_04]: My own sense of self is external to itself, that's not mine.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's why it's sometimes a bit ambiguous in the suttas as well, between that usage of internal and external.
[SPEAKER_04]: Sometimes internal basically stands synonymously as mind.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because that's where mind is.
[SPEAKER_04]: But, yeah, so you will start internally, stop assuming the external world, and in the end, that internal non-assumption of the external world and purification from attavāda is seen as a thing out there.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's like the body there to the extent necessary, the phenomenon, the image of the body, the memory of the body there, understood as body there,
[SPEAKER_04]: Practically speaking, again, nothing mystical about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: As I said, you can have a memory of something from 10 years ago, 10 days ago, or you can have a memory of what you're doing right now.
[SPEAKER_04]: The image of it is the memory of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Simultaneously present, enduring, giving the context to what you're attending.
[SPEAKER_04]: But stop putting yourself first as the one who remembers.
[SPEAKER_04]: Start seeing yourself as an enduring thing within that memory and directly in the world that's directly attended to.
[SPEAKER_04]: The objects of your attention, the senses.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's six senses already.
[SPEAKER_04]: The mind and the five senses.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the experience as a whole.
[SPEAKER_04]: With this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: And any notion of self-ownership,
[SPEAKER_04]: Consciousness, everything else in between, feelings, decisions, past, future, plans, grief, joys, it's all within these two, that are utterly inaccessible.
[SPEAKER_04]: And these two sticks hold each other.
[SPEAKER_04]: And everything that's dear to me, or not dear to me, is just sitting there on top of it gratuitously.
[SPEAKER_03]: I cannot be mine.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, practice of sati, basically, is practice of memory of your present body posture.
[SPEAKER_04]: Memory, not direct attention.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, have a memory of your present body posture.
[SPEAKER_04]: Have a memory of your present enduring feeling.
[SPEAKER_04]: Have a memory of your present enduring thoughts.
[SPEAKER_04]: Again, memory of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, emphasize the memory point of view, not directly attending point of view.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's how that... well, that's how signs of the mind will become apparent.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's how the whole
[SPEAKER_04]: The shape of the ambiguous state of mind or feeling and the sense of self, that's how it's going to be discerned.
[SPEAKER_01]: That memory is uprooting atta in the sense of, yeah, no matter what choices I make...
[SPEAKER_01]: It's resetting, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's resetting the right order.
[SPEAKER_01]: I am, yeah, I have to be in the body posture, I have to be breathing... Yeah, yeah, exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that is important.
[SPEAKER_04]: And then, when you have inevitably thought that sort of took you away from the principle of this, this is,
[SPEAKER_04]: You don't negate it, try to get rid of it, stop thinking, focus.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_04]: You just have a memory of it, having it right here, right now.
[SPEAKER_04]: And it's there.
[SPEAKER_04]: And you realize, you do that long enough, the knowledge that it cannot, it's inconceivable for it to be outside of this, this is, will become established.
[SPEAKER_04]: And there is no going back from there.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's where it results in knowledge.
[SPEAKER_04]: Even if you stopped and recollecting the two views, Sotāpanna's knowledge cannot be undone, that it cannot be outside.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, I can ignore it because I'm too occupied, whatever, with the world, with the family, and sometimes you go back to lay life and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: It doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_04]: When I stop and think about it, the knowledge that it cannot be outside, so the entire domain, the gratuitous assumption of, you know, atta, living there, independent owner, and then the entire mass of suffering, that dependent on that deeply rooted perversion,
[SPEAKER_04]: It's gone.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, that's why there is no second arrow hitting in ārya-sāvaka, as the sutta described.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because there is no that far, far deeply perverted order that projected you out there even worse.
[SPEAKER_04]: circumstances than you already are in.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, yeah, craving is bad, conceit is bad, but not as bad as attabhāda.
[SPEAKER_04]: Not as bad as that level of perversion and ignorance of this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, see, the more you pervert it, the more you own it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Which means, the heavier it is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Which means, losing it, it's going to be far worse.
[SPEAKER_04]: Somebody with traces of conceit, if they were to lose their life, health, and so on, things that are dear to them, won't suffer.
[SPEAKER_04]: As the Buddha said, you will have, as a sotāpanna, you will have seven grains of sand of suffering left in comparison to the mountain Himalayas that you would have destroyed by getting the right view and ceasing to assume outside yourself.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because you know the escape.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, yeah, and factually, because the burden to great degree has been made inconceivable.
[SPEAKER_04]: But that's why also, like, the right view surpasses.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, understanding attavāda, freeing yourself from attavāda upādāna type, surpasses all the other upādānas.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then, even with attavāda, you're not necessarily automatically free, but they're all included within it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because attavāda is on the level with this, this, this.
[SPEAKER_04]: View of Sīlavātiparamāsa, Assumption of Sīlavātiparamāsa, isn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: Assumption of Sensuality, isn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: And all the other views?
[SPEAKER_04]: All the other views, it's all within this, where this, this is, which is the fundamental, is somebody who has understood it, is a Sotāpanna, is free from animāda, but might not be free from sensuality, ill-will, and all the other things that are in between.
[SPEAKER_03]: Can we explore this discourse, where Buddha talks to Rahula about these five elements?
[SPEAKER_03]: And then he starts talking first about earth elements, and then he mentions, like, half the head, half the body, skin, teeth, and all.
[SPEAKER_04]: Be like earth, be like water.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then he says, you know, that which is internally clung to or held as mine.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then he says, well, but internal earth element and external earth element, both are earth elements.
[SPEAKER_03]: Can we say, against the background of our discussion, that we can also contemplate, let's put it by saying, you cannot just have internal earth elements, you cannot just have external earth elements.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Basically, you need to have both for any of this to be.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: For all elements.
[SPEAKER_04]: And even that would also could stand for the principle of this, this is.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's exactly what I'm trying to get at, whether that would be a valid approach to that discourse.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's what it is like on the level, I see,
[SPEAKER_04]: It's not on the level of directly attending and touching earth and staring at clay pots and so on, as they did the practice of casinos, mistakenly.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like, oh, you stare at that and that's how you see it.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, it's recollecting the great earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: Have a memory of what you're already in.
[SPEAKER_04]: Solidity.
[SPEAKER_04]: The experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_04]: Solidity.
[SPEAKER_04]: You could have it in different factors, but in this case, he was talking about earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: Be like earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: So,
[SPEAKER_04]: Recall the properties of earth that's currently enduring.
[SPEAKER_04]: Earth is not elsewhere now, while we talk about and forget about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: You are on earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: Factually, it's there, endures, as a basis for your experience.
[SPEAKER_04]: What are the properties of that external earth?
[SPEAKER_04]: It's like, okay, so can this internal earth, one that I'm paired with, partake in any properties that are outside?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: Inconceivable.
[SPEAKER_04]: Sustain that image with this, this is, and with this is, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: There will be no room for the ownership to remain there, clinging to this part or that part, or, oh, no way, I'm not this body, but I'm the universe, and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Which universe?
[SPEAKER_04]: The one that changes against your will all the time, like forcefully, violently, disrupts, erupts, gets destroyed?
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, well, that's not, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because those words are similar.
[SPEAKER_04]: Look at these great mountains.
[SPEAKER_04]: They come to destruction.
[SPEAKER_04]: They get destroyed, eventually.
[SPEAKER_04]: What is to be said about this tiny little fickle pebble, in relation to the size of this thing, that's equally, sort of, just unpredictable.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, with this, this is, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: The properties, the properties of this, cannot not be the properties of this inferior thing.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's the practice of casinos, in the nutshell.
[SPEAKER_04]: The element of earth, fire, and to the point of the element of consciousness, the most refined.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the point, for every casino, the Buddha said, and thus, a Brahmin would establish his mind on the level of that great earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: Anything inferior to that cannot perturb him.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, if you establish, like recollect, have a memory of presently enduring Earth while you're here on it, so to speak.
[SPEAKER_04]: All the time, think about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, what you're going to have is what people have today when they worry about what will happen to the Earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: They're going to get this anxiety.
[SPEAKER_04]: They call it eco-anxiety or something.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because, well, even if it's not ecology-related, you're going to have anxiety if you are not relinquishing your sense of self, if you don't know what comes first and what to look for.
[SPEAKER_04]: Because you realize you are, factually, your... all of your life's concerns, joys, as I said, possessions, future, past, all of that, well, presupposes this enduring planet of Earth, this great lump of soil,
[SPEAKER_04]: To exist, to be simultaneously present, as an uncontrollable, unownable basis that you are bound with.
[SPEAKER_04]: If something were to happen to that earth, nothing, nothing inferior.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, if your mind is established on that level, i.e.
[SPEAKER_04]: relinquish the ownership of everything inferior, any inferior change to that cannot bother you.
[SPEAKER_04]: But then the Buddha says, however, those Brahmins, they could factually establish the mind in the right order, on the right level, to a right extent,
[SPEAKER_04]: He did not know the escape, the danger, the gratification, the danger and the escape in regard to the element of that great earth, in regard to the water, fire, air, consciousness.
[SPEAKER_04]: Tathāgata knows it.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that's why he's free in both regards.
[SPEAKER_04]: See, those brahmins, outside of the guru's dispensation, who developed the mind on the level of the earth, have, to some extent, put it first.
[SPEAKER_04]: They did not see that that earth, that earth that you have the memory of, well, you wouldn't have such a memory, knowledge, recollection, image, if it weren't for this here, immediate earth.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, with this, this is what they couldn't see.
[SPEAKER_04]: Kind of mystifying it, in a way.
[SPEAKER_04]: They went too much that side or too far this side.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, they saw a certain, obviously, relationship of surmounting, but they didn't see that that great earth is defined as such on account of this little body that touches, smells, tastes, oozes, and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's why the entire universe is within this body.
[SPEAKER_04]: That is the measure of the universe and the universe then defines this body.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, with this, this is.
[SPEAKER_04]: But it's upādāna again.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, but yeah, if somebody who is still concerned with this inferior, internal, me, my body, sense of earth, basically, if you, like what the Buddha gave the advice to Rākula, if you actually cultivate and apply to yourself the properties of that great earth, that's unbothered by these inferior changes, and when people throw stuff on it, and dig it, and destroy it, it makes no difference to it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Apply those same properties to this internal, because it is the same thing.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's the elements.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's your ownership that created and gets you this division in mind.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's it, yeah.